# Chirag Agarwal

## Ph.D. Candidate — Computer Vision & Deep Learning

Chicago, IL, USA

ightharpoonup chiragagarwall12@gmail.com  $\diamond$  ightharpoonup chiragagarwall12  $\diamond$  ightharpoonup +1.312.478.1132  $\diamond$  ightharpoonup chiragagarwall

**Biography:** Chirag is a Ph.D. Candidate at the University of Illinois at Chicago. He has been actively researching in Image processing, Computer Vision, and Deep Learning for the last 7 years. Currently, his research interests are in Deep Neural Networks, specifically developing novel architectures, explaining and improving the robustness performance of deep networks.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL

Aug 2014 - Present

Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engg. — Deep Learning Advisors: Dan Schonfeld and Anh Nguyen

Thesis: The robustness and explainability of Deep Neural Networks

University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL

2017

M.S. in Electrical & Computer Engg. — Human Activity Recognition Advisor: Jezekiel Ben-Arie

Future Institute of Engg. & Management, Kolkata, India

2008 - 2012

B.S. in Electronics & Communication Engg.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages

Python, MATLAB, R

Libraries

PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, NLTK, OpenCV, scikit

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### University of Illinois at Chicago

Aug 2016 - Present

Chicago, IL

Research Assistant under Dr. Dan Schonfeld

- · Conceptualized unstructured Neural Networks, which overcomes the limitations of traditional sequential feedforward architectures.
- · Developed robust deep learning architectures by learning discriminative feature representations of the inputs.
- · Developed generative explainable AI algorithms having higher object localization accuracy and robustness across different hyperparameters.
- · Developed TreatNet, a LSTM based deep learning framework, for automatically generating beat-to-beat blood pressure using othe physiological signals.

#### Auburn University

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Auburn, AL

Research Assistant under Dr. Anh Nguyen

- · Integrated a generative inpainter into different explainable AI algorithms to remove salient input features.
- · Our generative algorithms resulted in (1) more plausible counterfactual samples under the true data generating process; (2) hyperparameter robustness; and (3) better object localization.
- · Performed the first systematic study on the sensitivity of explainable AI algorithms to changes in the input hyper-parameters—a phenomenon previously overlooked in the interpretability field.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Robert Bosch LLC (Supervisor: Dr. Ye Mao)

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Computer Vision / Augmented Reality Intern

Sunnyvale, CA

- · Developed novel methods for obtaining discriminative representations of images for tasks like recognition and identification.
- · Generated a 3-D dataset, using Microsoft Kinect, for developing novel Augmented Reality (AR) applications in Microsoft Hololens.

**Tempus labs Inc.** (Supervisor: Dr. Stephen Yip)

Jan 2018 - May 2018

Imaging Science Intern

Chicago, IL

- $\cdot$  Developed unsupervised machine learning algorithms for detecting malignant cells in breast cancer mammogram images.
- · Applied state-of-the-art deep learning methods for analyzing pathology images.

**Kitware Inc.** (Supervisor: Dr. Eran Swears) Research and Development Intern May 2017 - August 2017 Clifton Park, NY

- · Applied state-of-the-art object detection, motion-tracking and image segmentation algorithms for DARPA projects.
- · Benchmarked VIRAT video dataset, comprising both ground and aerial videos, using CNN and LSTM models.

Geisinger Health Systems (Supervisor: Dr. Mohammad Arbabshirani)
Research Intern

May 2016 - August 2016 Danville, PA

- · Quantified volume of adipose tissue from abdominal CT scans with 97% accuracy using Greedy Snake's algorithm.
- · Created a dynamic tool using MATLAB that automatically segments and calculates volume of adipose tissues.
- · Contributed to other research projects resulting in 3 conference and 1 journal publications.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=AFEjd1QAAAAJ&hl=en

## Journal papers

- · C. Agarwal, J. Klobusicky, and D. Schonfeld: Convergence of backpropagation with momentum for network architectures with skip connections, *Journal of Computational Mathematics (under review)*, 2019.
- · E. Cha, Y. Veturi, <u>C. Agarwal</u>, M. Arbabshirani and S. Pendergrass: Using Adipose Measures from Electronic Health Record Imaging Based Data for Discovery, *Journal of Obesity*, 2018.

#### Conference papers

- · C. Agarwal, N. Bansal, and A. Nguyen: The Sensitivity of Interpretability Methods to Hyperparameters. (Under review)
- · <u>C. Agarwal</u>, D. Schonfeld, and A. Nguyen: Removing input features via a generative model to explain their attributions to classifier's decisions. (Under review)
- · C. Agarwal, A. Nguyen, and D. Schonfeld: Improving Adversarial Robustness by Encouraging Discriminative Features, *ICIP 2019*.
- · C. Agarwal, N. Khobragade. Multi-class segmentation of neuronal electron microscopy images using deep learning, SPIE Medical Imaging, 2018.
- · <u>C. Agarwal</u>, M. Sharifzadeh, D. Schonfeld. CrossEncoders: A complex neural network compression framework accepted for oral presentation at the Visual Information Processing and Communication Conference, at *IS&T Electronic Imaging 2018*
- · M. Sharifzadeh, C. Agarwal, M. Aloraini, D. Schonfeld. Convolutional Neural Network Steganalysis's Application to Steganography, *IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP)*, 2017.
- · C. Agarwal, A. Dallal, M.R. Arbabshirani, A. Patel, and G. Moore. Unsupervised Quantification of Abdominal Fat from CT images using Greedy Snakes, SPIE Medical Imaging, 2017.
- · M.R. Arbabshirani, A. Dallal, <u>C. Agarwal</u>, A. Patel, and G. Moore. Accurate Segmentation of Lung fields on Chest Radiographs using Deep Convolutional Networks, *SPIE Medical Imaging*, 2017.

## E-print articles

- C. Agarwal, B. Dong, D. Schonfeld, and A. Hoogs: An Explainable Adversarial Robustness Metric for Deep Learning Neural Networks, arXiv preprint, 2018.
- · C. Agarwal, M. Sharifzadeh, J. Klobusicky, D. Schonfeld. CrossNets: Cross-Information Flow in Deep Learning Architectures, arXiv preprint, 2018.

#### ACADEMIC SERVICES

REFERENCES

Reviewing Conference papers:: ICIP, ICLR President of UIC ECE Journal Club

Tresident of the Bell bournar than

More available upon requests

Dr. Dan Schonfeld: Professor, University of Illinois at Chicago

Dr. Anh Nguyen: Assistant Professor, Auburn University,

dans at uic.edu anhnguyen at auburn.edu